Well, he was lying there,
and somebody hit me
over the head, and
that's all I remember.
Hm.
Here, I'll take over, Phil.
Oh.
You don't have to read
me my rights, lieutenant.
I already know 'em. Heh.
Are you all right, counselor?
Oh, I guess so.
Well, we got a gunshot
report about 9:00
from a man who
lives across the street.
Same man that saw you
drive up ten minutes later.
Oh-ho.
Did he see anybody else?
Car drive away.
Ah. It wouldn't
happen to have been
a late-model blue sedan?
Yeah. Ah.
That's the same one that
was here the other day.
You know these are
dangerous people,
and you're... You're
right there in the middle.
Next time, you could get hurt.
What am I gonna do about it?
Ben, are you all right?
Cassie, what are you doing here?
Somebody call you?
Yeah. One of my men. Huh.
I figured you'd better
get to the hospital
and get a x-ray. You
might have a concussion.
Huh. Free to go.
Okay. Thanks, lieutenant.
Mm-hm.
Uh, I'm sorry they
drug you in on this.
I'm okay. Are you sure?
Oh, sure.
Oh.
Oh. Hm.
You don't mind driving me?
Of course not. Oh.
A little woozy?
A little bit. Heh.
Uh, i-is your car
radio still broken?
Yeah.
That's good.
I'm going up.
Don't touch me.
I don't have a gun or a
knife or even a pencil,
so don't put your hands on me.
Mr. Gerard?
Mr. Matlock.
Where is he?
I think you'd better
leave, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Gerard?
Where are they going?
On a trip.
They gonna start a little, uh,
shooting match
with the Benedicts?
We don't start anything.
They did that when
they killed that witness.
We don't know they
killed that witness.
Mr. Gerard... we...
We have to take this stuff
one step at a time.
If you let it escalate,
everybody loses.
Particularly your son.
When it suits your
purpose, he's my son.
Well, uh...
We have that in common.
All right, tequila all around!
On Tyler Hudson!
Oye.
He asks if you're
interested in a car.
If it's the right kind.
Has, um... Mrs.
Martinez been in today?
Just what you do want?
I was just wondering, uh,
does anybody around here
drive a full-size
maroon station wagon?
Why? Well, last night,
a fellow by the name
of Mickey Morrison
got himself killed.
And, uh, it seems that
someone who drives
a full-size maroon station
wagon might be involved.
It means nothing to
me. What's it to you?
Well, it seems that whoever
killed Mickey Morrison
might really be the person that
killed Congressman McGinnis,
and the talk is
that that someone...
could maybe be you.
Now, why would I do
such an outrageous thing?
Well, talk also is that when
it comes to the distribution
of illegal drugs in this city,
that you and your
family are number one.
An ugly, unfounded rumor.
Well, there's also talk
that the investigation
Congressman
McGinnis was conducting
threatened to shut down
your entire operation.
Pure fiction.
Talk also is, is that you're
a very smart woman.
I confess.
And the word is that
someone in your group
stabbed the congressman
and framed Craig Gentry,
knowing that his father
would blame his old enemy,
Carl Benedict, and
start a war for revenge.
Now, while the Benedicts
and the Gerards were busy
killing each other off,
then you and your gang...
Your "family..." would move
in and establish yourselves
as number one in the city.
You know something?
That's a hell of a good
idea. I wish I'd thought of it.
Hm.
Get out.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you for your time.
Good morning, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Benedict's expecting you.
Well, I should hope so.
So you got me down for 5
on the home team, right, Jimmy?
Right.
Thank you for coming
by, Mr. Matlock.
Didn't seem I had much choice.
I'd like to get something
on the record with you,
since you now
work for the Gerards.
So tell this to Sam...
I don't work for the Gerards.
Now, you listen to what
I have to say, please.
We do not want a war.
We have nothing
to do with any of this.
I did not kill Mickey Morrison.
He was gonna help put the son
of the man I hate away for life.
Why would I kill him?
Well, how about this?
You paid him to
give false testimony,
and then he reneged on the
deal, and so you killed him.
How about that?
Paul. Come over here, please.
I'd like you to sit in
that chair, please.
Yes, sir.
Tom. Yeah?
Take out your gun
and cover Paul.
Tom, you will count to ten.
When you reach ten,
you will pull the trigger,
unless I tell you to stop.
Paul... I want you
to tell me the truth.
I always tell you the truth.
Now, who is my right-hand
man around here, Paul?
Count.
I am. TOM: One.
You know everything that
goes on around here, don't you?
Two.
You know I do.
Three.
Did I kill Congressman McGinnis?
Four. No.
Do you know who did?
Five. No.
Please, Mr. Benedict.
Six.
Do you know who killed
that witness last night?
Seven. No!
Eight.
The truth! Nine.
I don't know. For
God's sakes, Carl!
Wait a minute!
Stop.
Put your gun away, Tom.
Paul doesn't lie, Mr. Matlock.
I warned you about
dangerous people.
Mr. Benedict, I'm
Lieutenant Webber.
I don't understand.
Somebody shoots up your
place, and you don't see anybody?
It all happened very fast.
What about you, Mr. Matlock?
Well, to tell you the
truth, I didn't see much.
I saw a lot of floor and
underneath the tables.
I... I gave my
statement to the officer.
All right. Thank you.
Uh... Hey, um, lieutenant.
Carl Benedict is sure it was
the Gerard group who did this.
Uh-huh.
You may have a
really hot potato here.
My potato's not any hotter
than yours, you know.
These gentlemen are
here to see Mr. Gerard.
Mr. Gerard?
Yes?
These two officers
want to see you.
Hey!
Mr. Gerard's been hit.
How is he?
He's still in surgery.
Oh.
You want a cup of coffee?
Thanks.
Mm.
Heh. You, uh...
Do you remember
being a little boy?
What?
Being a little boy.
I remember.
I mean, I remember things.
Heh-heh.
Seems like a long time ago.
Hell, it was a long time ago.
But I remember.
There you go.
I bet when you were a little
boy, you thought he was it.
I mean, I bet you thought he
was the greatest, didn't you?
Hm.
Mm.
They, uh...
They had to take out his spleen,
but he... He's gonna be in
intensive care for a while,
but he's... He's
gonna be all right.
I mean, at least
that's what they say.
Oh.
He's a lucky man.
That's good.
Uh, you want to see him?
No.
Tequila all around,
courtesy of Tyler Hudson!
What is it this time?
The shootout at
the Benedict house.
Oh, you know, by the way,
that Sam Gerard got
shot a couple times?
I heard.
You shouldn't have used
a maroon station wagon.
That's how I knew it was you.
Váyanse.
Whoa.
You have 60 seconds to
convince me not to use this.
All right. I took a look
around in the back
before I came inside.
I saw the maroon station
wagon in the garage.
Now, the bullet holes
that are in there now
were not there
before the shootout
and can be used for the
process of identification.
Now, the Gerards know that
they didn't shoot
up the Benedicts,
and Sam's hit was
a retaliatory gesture.
So as you can understand,
both sides are more
than a little upset.
If they find out
what you have done,
you can depend on having
a very fine and splendid funeral
in the very near future.
Now, I have left the
best parts of this story
on Ben Matlock's
answering machine,
because I never travel
without insurance.
Mm.
Hi.
Hello.
Don't shoot, okay?
Hello in there.
Hello, Carl?
Hello, Tom?
Hello, Paul.
Now, don't shoot.
I've got somebody
I'd like you all to meet.
So stand back...
keep a good thought,
and kind of aim your
guns towards the ground.
This person... This
person may very well be
an answer to our problems.
So say hello to good news.
Now, if there's any more trouble
between now and
the end of the trial,
I'm telling you,
your son might as well
just plan to go to prison.
I'm appreciate what you're
trying to do, Mr. Matlock,
but I'm not sure.
You're not going
to believe this.
Carl Benedict is
here, and he's alone.
Why is he here?
I asked him to come.
Show him in.
Hello, Carl.
Sam.
It's been a long time.
Yes, it has.
How's your father?
You know him. He never changes.
Give him my regards.
Sam, we were only acting
out of what we thought
was self-defense.
We don't want a war with you.
I came here personally as an
act of good faith to tell you this.
I'm truly sorry about
what happened.
I accept that.
Thank you for coming.
Good night.
All right, Mr. Matlock.
I'll agree to your suggestion.
Good.
How's Craig?
Um... he's holding up.
Do you have any
children, Mr. Matlock?
Yes.
You get along?
That's good.
Um, I will... I'll come again.
Leave us.
Mr. Gerard has agreed
to a proposal I made
that may get us by our
immediate problems here.
I'm listening.
Somebody must've
seen Craig Gentry
after 8:30 the
night of the murder.
Your people cover the streets.
Find someone who saw him.
You're asking a lot.
I have a big problem
with a prosecution witness
who says he saw my client
enter the victim's office
building at that time.
It is essential that I provide
him with a legitimate alibi.
There's no guarantee I
can find you someone.
I know that. But if you can,
Sam Gerard would consider it
repayment for all the
trouble you've caused him.
And it would go some
distance in demonstrating
that you didn't frame
Craig Gentry yourself.
That'll be $5.50.
Hey, didn't I see you on TV?
Yeah.
You're the guy who
said he saw Craig Gentry
go into that building over there
the night somebody killed
the congressman, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Is this about the same place
you parked that night?
So what if it was?
Well, when you
saw him, was he...?
Was he coming from
that direction over there
or from that direction
back over there?
What do you want
to know that for?
O-or was he just standing
in front of the door there?
I mean, how long
were you watching him?
You know, five seconds,
ten seconds. What?
Hey, who are you? Well,
I'm certainly not the guy
that paid you to perjure
yourself, that's for sure.
And I also know about
your two felony convictions.
Just give me my money
and get out of the cab.
Hey, you're gonna get a
second chance, you know.
They're gonna call
you back to the stand.
And this time, I wouldn't lie...
'cause you can't spend
your money in jail.
Oh, Mr. Silvers...
you testified earlier
that you saw the defendant
going into an office building,
uh, at 15589 Peachtree
around 8:25 the
night of the murder.
That's right.
Mr. Silvers, are
you nearsighted?
Do you wear glasses?
Yeah.
Were you wearing glasses
the night of the murder?
Yeah.
According to this copy
of a bill from your optometrist,
your glasses were being
repaired the night of the murder.
That's right, they were.
But I was wearing these.
I always carry my spares.
Heh.
Oh-ho.
Well... I guess...
I guess you could see as well
that night as you ever have.
That's right.
Have you been... back
to the building
since the murder?
As a matter of fact, I took
a fare over there last night.
Would you recognize
that person again?
As a matter of fact,
that's him sitting right there
at the end of the first row.
For the record, he's
identified Tyler Hudson.
Did you see anybody
else last night?
Yeah. You.
Me?
Yeah, that's right. You and him
were standing at
the front door, talking.
Oh, wh...?
About what time was
that? Do you recall?
Around 8:30.
Are you as certain
you saw me last night as you are
about seeing Craig Gentry
the night of the murder?
You bet I am.
You know... the problem...
with your seeing
me last night...
was I was here
last night at 8:30
with the deputy
district attorney
discussing, uh,
jury instructions.
There.
That's the man
you saw last night,
and you thought it was me.
You tricked me.
Oh, well.
Of course I did.
Tricked you, huh? Yeah.
Are you still sure
it was Craig Gentry
you saw outside that building
the night of the murder?
Well, you... Withdraw
the question.
Nothing further.
Redirect?
No, Your Honor.
If the court please,
the state rests.
This court is adjourned
until 9 a.m. Monday morning,
at which time we'll hear
the case for the defense.
You saw Craig Gentry that night.
I was going past the
Blue Moose Bar, when...
How did you know it was him?
I saw him on the
TV. On the news.
And you're willing to testify?
Yes, sir.
Tell Mr. Gerard
this evens things.
No, I have a few more things
I need to clear with Miss Lynn.
What were you doing the night
the congressman was murdered?
I was at my boyfriend Jack's.
I remember watching
a news bulletin about it,
uh, the next morning
during breakfast.
We are engaged, by the way.
And how is it you happened
to see Craig Gentry?
Well, I ran out to
get a couple things
at a deli near Jack's condo.
What was the name of
the deli? Do you recall?
Mm, sure. Simon's Deli.
Oh, Simon's. We take
out from there all the time.
Mr. Matlock loves
their chicken salad.
And that's where
you saw Craig Gentry?
No. No, no. I saw him
through the window
at the Blue Moose Lounge.
That's a place
you've got to pass
to get the deli
from Jack's condo.
Anyway, I saw Mr. Gentry
sitting at the bar.
And what time was that?
About 9, 9:15.
You're sure about the time?
Yes.
Now, the time is very important.
If you saw Craig
Gentry in that bar at 9:15,
then he couldn't have been
at the congressman's
office building.
And you're positive
that it was Craig Gentry.
Positive.
After all, I... I did
see him twice.
Oh, you made two
trips to Simon's?
Like I said, I ran down there
around 9 to pick up some sodas.
And then around 11 or
so, Jack and I were starving,
so I ran back down there again
to pick up some ham
and cheese sandwiches.
Ham and cheese.
Uh-huh.
Ham and cheese are
Jack's favorites. Ha-ha.
Anyway, when I... I went past
the Blue Moose the second time,
I looked in the
window and I noticed
he was still sitting at the bar.
That'll be all, Miss Lynn.
I can go?
Uh, Ms. Martinez
will be in touch.
Okay. Oh, nice
to meet all of you.
Goodbye.
Problem?
Did she owe you, or
was she strictly for hire?
What are you saying?
Simon's a kosher deli.
You can't get a ham
sandwich from there.
Well, I thought she
was pretty effective.
All she needs is
a little rehearsing.
What we need is a
legitimate witness.
Hm.
Nice try.
You'll put in a good
word with Mr. Gerard?
Absolutely.
Morning, Cassie.
Let me know when Ben comes in.
I'll be in Michelle's office.
Oh, he's already here.
Hm?
He's not due until 11.
Well, he was here
when I got here.
He said he didn't
want to be disturbed.
How is he?
Well, let's put it this way:
He's not playing the ukulele.
I'll see if I can cheer him up.
Uh, better not.
He's in there with
somebody. Who?
Mr. Morgenstern from
the Taxi Licensing Board.
Now, what's he doing with him?
Beats me.
All right, I'll just go
say good morning.
Good morning.
We're expected.
What's going on in there?
Am I late?
I wouldn't know.
Mr. Matlock's expecting me.
Uh, Mr. Atkins is
here. Go right in.
Thank you.
What's Ben doing?
I'm Carl Benedict.
They're expecting you.
Right in there.
Cassie, call over
to the TV station
and ask 'em if I can
look at that file tape again.
I'll meet you there.
The police are arriving now.
Maybe they can tell us more.
Officer?
Sir, any idea what's
happened up there?
Want to run it again?
Well... What are you doing?
We've been going
about this all wrong.
It's not who came out of
the building that's important.
It's who went in.
Lieutenant Webber...
uh, h-how long...
have you been with
the Atlanta police?
Seventeen years.
And how long have you been
with the Organized
Crime division?
Twelve years.
So 12 years
with the highest-grade
detective salary.
That would mean, what, you make,
what, $40-, 50,000 a year?
Objection. No relevancy.
Your Honor, I beg the
court's indulgence here.
All right. Overruled for now.
You may answer.
Yeah, that's about
what they pay.
So I guess with...
With, what, a pension
and medical and, uh,
overtime, you must...
But still, with
the... With prices
as high as they are,
it must be really difficult
to make ends meet.
I see where you're
going, counselor.
The departmental
regulations allow moonlighting,
and I do make some extra
money as a security consultant.
Oh. So that's how...
That's how I have a condominium
in Hawaii, as you have found,
and an Italian sports
car in my garage.
It's a good
investment. And a toy.
So what?
Well... yeah.
So I guess with,
uh... With this, uh...
The moonlighting...
The... The security
work that you do...
Uh, on an annual
basis, that's...
About $150,000.
You know what I'm gonna
ask before I ask it, don't you?
What do you do to
make that kind of money?
I told you, I'm a
security consultant.
Well, I mean, do you
put in alarm systems,
or build special
fences or hire guards?
Security, like a lot of things
now, is highly specialized,
and I know a
great deal about it.
One of your major clients
is, uh, Benedict Industries.
Uh, I'd have to, uh, consult
my records on that now.
You didn't anticipate
that question, did you?
And w-what...? What do you
do for Benedict Industries?
Give 'em a little, uh,
inside information?
Advance warning
of sting operations?
Objection. Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock's questions
are speculative and insulting.
Sustained.
You know better, Mr. Matlock.
Now, let's move along.
Yes, sir.
Let's follow this line.
Congressman McGinnis
comes down here
to investigate, uh,
local organized crime.
Oh, like, um, say... the, uh...
Benedict Industries.
You're appointed
liaison officer.
That's a happy coincidence.
The problem is...
Congressman McGinnis
was going to investigate
everything and everybody.
And sooner or
later, your connection
with the Benedict
family had to come up.
At the least, there would be
an Internal Affairs
investigation,
and maybe even criminal
charges against you.
Now, what do you think?
The congressman had to go...
and someone else
had to get the blame.
What do you think?
I think you're crazy.
Well, that may
be. I got a little...
The... The morning the
body was discovered,
you arrived at the building
with the other police officers?
Yes, that's right.
About what time was it?
About 7 a.m. About 7 a.m.
You know what happened?
There was a TV news crew
that arrived at that building
before the police did...
and they had their
cameras rolling.
They recorded everything.
Everybody who went in
and out of that building.
And the police have
looked at that tape.
And... And... And the
TV news people. I did.
Everybody looked at that tape
over and over and over again,
just hoping...
they might see somebody come out
of that building...
that could be the killer.
And you know what?
Everyone was accounted for.
That's right.
That's right. How about this?
I was looking at that
tape again this morning.
And it's in evidence, and
the jury will be viewing it.
I hadn't thought of it before.
But you know what...
I did not see, lieutenant?
I did not see you...
entering that building.
Well, I was there.
Oh, I have no doubt
that you were there.
But I don't think you entered
the building that morning.
I think... you had
been there all night.
Oh, no.
I think you... You waited,
as you had several
nights before,
for the congressman
to be alone in his offices.
And that night you killed him.
No.
And then you spent the night.
No. Yes.
And then the next morning,
when the police arrived,
you just folded
yourself in with them.
Your Honor... And
then you framed the man
you knew had had
two heated arguments
with the congressman,
Craig Gentry.
Lieutenant, you're...
You're not very good at this.
And I'm not talking about graft.
You may be pretty good at that.
I'm talking about...
committing murder...
and then placing the blame...
on someone else.
You're just not good at it.
There were too many mistakes.
When you planned this,
did you have any idea
whose toes you'd be stepping on?
I didn't plan anything.
Let's speculate.
You planted the murder
weapon in Mr. Gentry's home
while you were searching it.
No.
You destroyed his alibi
by paying Mickey
the bartender to lie.
You further
incriminated Mr. Gentry
by paying Dick Silvers
to commit perjury.
That's not true.
Your Honor, I object.
Can Mr. Matlock
substantiate any of this?
You betcha.
A moment longer, Your Honor?
Proceed.
I'm afraid it is true.
That's what I meant by
"you're not very good at this."
When a... When a person has to
lie himself, that's one thing.
But when you have to
pay someone else to lie...
You had to kill Mickey
when it became apparent
he was gonna come forward
and tell the truth, didn't you?
No.
But Dick Silvers,
he played his part
beautifully, didn't he?
I don't know what
else to tell you. No.
How long have you
known Dick Silvers?
I first laid eyes on him
when he came
forward after the murder.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Mr. Silvers has had
an interesting history.
Two felony convictions,
31 arrests in the
past seven years.
Isn't that right?
Could be, yeah.
He's worked for you for a
number of years, hasn't he?
Objection. Your Honor?
Go ahead.
He has, hasn't he?
No. As a gofer,
a sometimes private detective,
uh, um, an informant.
Kind of your connection with
the underworld, so to speak.
I've used a lot of people,
but he was not one of them.
You pay these
informants sometimes.
Sometimes you see to it
that they... avoid prosecution
when they give you
information, is that right?
It's common practice, yeah.
So, what did you
do for Dick Silvers
to get him to lie about
seeing Craig Gentry?
I did nothing. And I am
not aware of his lying.
What, did you get him a new cab?
No.
You did get him his
own taxi franchise
so he wouldn't have to drive
for a fleet anymore, didn't you?
No.
He does have his own cab
and taxi seal, doesn't he?
You tell me.
This is Defense Exhibit
F for identification.
By law, an applicant
for a city cab franchise
must not have gotten
a felony conviction
in the prior five years,
but that requirement
can be waived
with a recommendation
from a law enforcement
or judicial officer.
Now, this is a certified copy
of Mr. Silvers' application.
What does it say
in the upper right?
"Approved Atlanta
P.D. endorsement."
The application doesn't reveal
the endorser's name, does it?
I don't see it, no.
Public documents don't
carry that information.
This is Defense Exhibit
G for identification.
This is a certified copy
of a document entitled,
"Memo of Franchise Approval."
And it's signed
by Commissioner
Morgenstern himself.
Would you read what it says
on the second line, lieutenant?
Just... It's right...
Right... Right there.
Right there. You see?
It says... "Atlanta
Police endorsement
"by Lieutenant Chet Webber.
Noted for file."
It was noted for file.
See, that's... another mistake.
You just can't trust
these bureaucrats...
not to cover for
themselves, can you?
We find the defendant,
Craig Gentry, not guilty.
The jury having found
the defendant not guilty,
this court is adjourned.
All right.
Congratulations.
Tyler, thank you.
All right. Uh, Ben. Thanks.
I'll see you back at the office.
Dad?
I, uh...
I've been thinking
a lot about...
that night... ten years ago...
when I walked out.
And the worst
thing about it was...
The worst thing about it
was that I never said goodbye.
Goodbye.
www.tvsubtitles.net